Rockbridge Historical Society Biographical Collection RHS.Coll.0033
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Rockbridge Historical Society Biographical Collection
Date Not Yet Determined
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
RHS.Coll.0033
12 Box
Scope and Contents
This collection contains biographical and historical information on various people and places.
- A (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes folders on Jean Cameron Agnew, Jeannie O. Abbott, John Agnor, Andrew Alexander, Archibald Alexander, John Alexander, Louise Houston Alexander, William Alexander, Archer Anderson, Ellen Anderson, Joseph Anderson, William A. Anderson, Armentrout, and Jacob Arnold.
  - Abbot, Jeannie O. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes financial deed from 1890, authorized capital bond from Buena Vista Cassimere Mills from 1891, bond from People's National Bank in Lynchburg from 1891, and a hand written bond noting terms of loans from 1893.
  - Agnew, Jean Cameron (Box 1, Folder 2)
    This folder includes a biographical essay by Mrs. Henry Drennan Agnew (no date) and a scrapbook, also assembled by Mrs. Henry Agnew, which includes newspaper clippings about Jean Agnew (1934-1935).
    Agnew, Jean Cameron, 1877-1955
  - Agnor, John (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, Andrew (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Alexander, Andrew
  - Alexander, Archibald (Box 1, Folder 5)
    This folder contains a photo of Archibald Alexander's house, dated 1845.
    Alexander, Archibald
  - Alexander, John (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Alexander, John, Major
  - Alexander, Louise Houston (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Alexander, Louise Houston
  - Alexander, William (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, Archer (Box 1, Folder 9)
    This folder includes a 1918 publication on Archer Anderson and his time spent as a director of Tredegar Iron Works in Richmond, Virginia.
  - Anderson, Ellen (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Anderson, Ellen Graham
  - Anderson, Joseph (Box 1, Folder 11)
    This folder contains three gelatin silver photo copies that depict a "patriotic celebration" held on behalf of William A. Anderson from 1917. The original photo was developed by J.T. Miller at 28 Main St. Lexington, Virginia.
    Anderson, Joseph Reid
  - Anderson, William A. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Anderson, William Alexander
  - Armentrout (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arnold, Jacob (Box 1, Folder 14)
- B (Box 2, Folder 15-32)
  Includes folders on George A. Baker, Barclay, Mr. and Mrs. Hassie Barry, Thomas H. Benton, Daniel Blain, Mrs. Lewis H. Blair, BlakeyJohn Bower, Dr. Elliott T. Brady, John Mercer Brooke, Brooks Family, Manley Brown, Mary Moore Brown, Sally White Bruce, Thomas Bruce, Samuel Burks, and Burns family
  - Baker, George A. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    This folder includes two photo negatives that depict George and Mary Baker. The developed portraits are included as well.
    Baker, George A.
  - Barclay, William Houston (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Barclay, William Houston
  - Barry, Hassie, Mr. and Mrs. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    This folder includes a bound copy of typed interview transcripts between Hassie Barry and Eleanor Connor on behalf of Lime Kiln Arts from November 12th, 1994. Transcribed by Rockbridge Reports.
  - Benton, Thomas H. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Benton, Thomas Hart
  - Blain, Daniel (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Blain, Daniel
  - Blair, Louis H. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Blakey (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bowyer, John (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Bowyer, John
  - Brady, Dr. Elliot T. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooke, John Mercer (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooks Family (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Brooks family
  - Brown, Manley (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Brown, Manley
  - Brown, Mary Moore (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bruce, Sally White (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Bruce, Sallie White
  - Bruce, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Burks, Samuel (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Buers (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Burns Family (Box 2, Folder 32)
- C (Box 3, Folder 33-61)
  Includes folders on Campbell/Houston family, Edmund D. Campbell, Harry D. Campbell, John Lyle Campbell, John Poage Campbell, Leslie Lyle Campbell, Robert F. Campbell, Robert K. Campbell, W. A. Campbell, William S. Campbell, Horace Caruthers, John A. Champe, Chapin family, Chittum, John Coalter, Christopher Columbus, Robert Page Cooke, Mary Beard Copper, Rev. John Craig, Jane Todd Crawford, James S. A. Crawford, Crozet family, Ernest Cummings, and Cunningham family.
  - Campbell Family (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Campbell family
  - Campbell, Edmund D. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Campbell, Edmund Douglas
  - Campbell, Harry D. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Campbell, Henry Donald
  - Campbell, John L. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    This folder includes a manuscript copy of John Lyle Campbell's work "Silurian Formation in Western Virginia," published in the American Journal of Science and ARts, Vol. XVIII, 1879.
    Campbell, J. L. (John Lyle)
  - Campbell, John Lyle (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Campbell, John Poage (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Campbell, Leslie Lyle (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Campbell, L. L. (Leslie Lyle)
  - Campbell, Robert F. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    This folder includes a scrapbook made from a First Presbyterian Church (Asheville, N.C.) program pamphlet and newspaper clippings about Robert Campbell. The pamphlet is from a 1943 memorial of Campbell.
    Campbell, Robert Fishburne
  - Campbell, Robert K. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Campbell, William Addison (Box 3, Folder 42)
    This folder contains a scrapbook with a variety of personal writings, journal entries, and correspondence to and from William Anderson Campbell. Letters date back to 1882. Newspaper obituaries are included following personal writing and ephemera.
    Campbell, William Addison
  - Campbell, William S. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    This folder contains two photos of William S. Campbell as a child and as a young man. No dates available.
  - Caruthers, Horace (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Caruthers, Horace
  - Caruthers, William A. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    Caruthers, William Alexander
  - Champe, John A. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Champe, J. A.
  - Chapin, Laura (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Chittum, Charles (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Two copies of a pamphlet called 'The Story of Finding the Coffin in which Gen. Robert E. Lee was afterward Buried'
    Chittum, Charles H.
  - Coalter, John (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Columbus, Christopher (Box 3, Folder 50)
    This folder contains 4 photographs that display a 1492 English translation of Christopher Colombus' Log Book on his initial journey to the Americas.
    Columbus, Christopher
  - Cooke, Robert Page (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Cooke, Robert Page
  - Copper, Mary Beard (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Copper, Mary Beard
  - Corbin, Margaret (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Corbin, Margaret
  - Craig, Reverend John (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Crawford, Jane Todd (Box 3, Folder 55)
    This folder contains a number of publications and complete magazines reflecting on Jane Crawford's abdominal surgery performed by Ephraim McDowell, such as the Kentucky Medical Journal (1979) and Danville Magazine (1972). Furthermore, there is an illustrated print depicting the medical scene (based on a lithograph from 1880).
  - Crawford, Jane Todd - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Crawford, Jane Todd - Newspaper Clippings (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Crawford, James A. (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Crozet, Claudius (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Crozet, Claudius, 1790-1864
  - Cummings, Ernest (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Cummings, Ernest Oliver
  - Cunningham (Box 3, Folder 61)
- D (Box 4, Folder 62-81)
  Includes folders on Samuel Dale, Benjamin Darst, Pierre Daura, Davidson, Charles Andrew Davidson, Greenlee Davidson, James Dorman Davidson, James M. Davidson, Jefferson Davis, Sam Davis, Benjamin Franklin Day, Marquis De Chastellus, Sally Bruce Dickinson, James Dabney Dix, Charles Squier Dod, Calvin M. Dold, Drake, and Dunlap.
  - Dale, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 62)
    Dale, Samuel, General
  - Darst, Benjamin Sr. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    Darst, Benjamin
  - Daura, Pierre (Box 4, Folder 64)
    This folder contains a woodblock print of a Pierre Daura Christmas card, depicting the birth of Jesus Christ. No dates available.
    Daura, Pierre
  - Davidson (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Davidson, Charles Andrew (Box 4, Folder 66)
    Davidson, Charles A. (Charles Andrew)
  - Davidson, Greenlee - Poem (Box 4, Folder 67)
    This folder includes a number of copies of a poem written by Greenlee Davidson's father commemorating his relationship with his mother following his death at the Battle of Chancellorsville on May 3rd, 1863.
    Davidson, Greenlee
  - Davidson, Greenlee - Poem (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Davidson, Greenlee - Biography (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Davidson, James Dorman (Box 4, Folder 70)
    Davidson, James D. (James Dorman)
  - Davidson, James M. (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Davis, Jefferson (Box 4, Folder 72)
    This folder contains a pamphlet from the Proclamation of the 100th Anniversary of the Birth of Jefferson Davis on June 3rd, 1908, officially dubbed a Confederate memorial day by the Hollywood Memorial association and endorsed by former Virginia Govenor, Claude A. Swanson. Pamphlet includes a photo of Davis.
    Davis, Jefferson
  - Davis, Sam (Box 4, Folder 73)
    This folder includes a pamphlet on Sam Davis written by Dr. H. M. Hamill entitled "The Story of an Old Fashion Boy," from 1908.
    Davis, Samuel H.
  - Day, Benjamin Franklin (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Day, Benjamin Franklin, Admiral
  - De Chastellus, Marquis (Box 4, Folder 75)
    DeChastellus, Marquis
  - Dickinson, Sally Bruce (Box 4, Folder 76)
    Dickinson, Sally Bruce
  - Dix, James Dabney (Box 4, Folder 77)
    This folder contains a biographical death record in the immediate days following James Dabney Dix's passing by his brother. No dates available.
    Dix, James Dabney
  - Dod, Charles Squier (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Dod, Charles S.
  - Dold, Calvin M. (Box 4, Folder 79)
    This folder contains 19th century ink blotters advertising insurance companies for which Dold was the Lexington agent as well as a biographical sketch of Dold.
    Dold, Calvin Morgan
  - Drake, G. Francis (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Dunlap, Henrietta (Box 4, Folder 81)
- E-I (Box 5, Folder 82-117)
  George William Effinger, Charles M. Figgat, Richard Fletcher, Augusta B. Fothergill, William Frazier, Jacob Fuller, Francis pendleton Gaines, James E. A. Gibbs, Gilbert McClung Gillespie, Gilmer Family, Ellen Glasgow, Nancy Gravatt, Michael Harmon, Robert Goodloe Harper, Haynes family, David Hays, John Hays, Hays family, Maude Henderson, Hickory Hill, Finley Willson Houston, K. H. Houston, Samuel Houston, Samuel Houston Jr., Rev. Samuel Houston, Thomas D. Houston, Houston Family, James Lewis Howe, Charles Hughes, margaret Jones Hull, Milton Wylie Humphreys, Richard C. Irby, and George Irwin.
  - Effinger, George Williams (Box 5, Folder 82)
    Effinger, George Williams
  - Figgat, Charles M. (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Fletcher, Richard (Box 5, Folder 84)
    Fletcher, Richard R.
  - Fothergill, Augusta B. (Box 5, Folder 85)
    Fothergill, Augusta B.
  - Frazier, William (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Fuller, Jacob (Box 5, Folder 87)
    This folder contains a teaching certificate for the Rockbridge County public free schools dated August 31, 1873 and a certificate of lifetime membership in the American Colonization Society dated August 25, 1846. The membership certificate is signed by the Society's president, Henry Clay, and secretary, William McLain.
    Fuller, Jacob
  - Gaines, Francis Pendleton (Box 5, Folder 88)
    This folder contains a pamphlet from the inauguration of Francis Pendleton Gaines as President of Washington and Lee University. Dated October 25th, 1930.
    Gaines, Francis Pendleton
  - Gibbs, James E. A. (Box 5, Folder 89)
    This folder contains 6 silver gellatin photographs and one photo negative depicting James Gibbs and his residence. No dates available.
    Gibbs, James Edward Allen, 1829 - 1902
  - Gibbs, James E. A. - Biography (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Gillespie, Gilbert McClung (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Gilmer Family (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Glasgow, Ellen (Box 5, Folder 93)
    Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson
  - Gravatt, Nancy (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Harmon, Michael (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Harper, Robert Goodloe, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    This folder contains a published speech given by Harper at the celebration of the recent triumphs of the cause of mankind in Germany dated January 20, 1814.
    Harper, Robert Goodloe
  - Haynes Family (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Hays, David (Box 5, Folder 98)
    Hays, David
  - Hays Family (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Hays, John (Box 5, Folder 100)
    Hays, John
  - Henderson, Maude (Box 5, Folder 101)
    Henderson, Maude Truxton
  - Hickory Hill (Box 5, Folder 102)
    This folder contains an October 1944 receipt for the sale of "Hickory Hill," a home in Rockbridge County.
  - Houston, Finley Wilson (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Houston, K. H. (Box 5, Folder 104)
    This folder contains a bound scrapbook with a variety of stickers and newspaper clipppings. No dates available.
  - Houston, Samuel (Box 5, Folder 105)
    This folder contains a pamphlet written by Sam Houston, dated March 3rd, 1825, which proffers his perspective on 19th century Tennessee state politics.
    Houston, Sam, 1793 - 1863
  - Houston, Samuel - Newspaper Clippings (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Houston, Samuel Reverend (Box 5, Folder 107)
    Houston, Samuel
  - Houston, Samuel Jr. (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Houston, Thomas D. (Box 5, Folder 109)
    This folder contains a detailed biography of Houston and a documents collection. No publication date available.
  - Houston Family (Box 5, Folder 110)
    Houston family
  - Howe, James Lewis (Box 5, Folder 111)
    Howe, James Lewis
  - Howe, James Lewis - Newspaper Clippings (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Hughes, Charles (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Hull, Margaret James (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Humphreys, Milton Wylie (Box 5, Folder 115)
    Humphreys, Milton W. (Milton Wylie)
  - Irby, Richard C. (Box 5, Folder 116)
    Irby, Richard M., Jr.
  - Irwin, George (Box 5, Folder 117)
    This folder contains personal correspondence between George Irwin and his mother, dated December 10th, 1917.
    Irwin, George Junkin
- J (Box 6, Folder 118-133)
  This box contains folders on George Jackson, Thomas Stonewall Jackson, Thomas Jefferson, Chauncy Jerome, Abner Nash Johnson, Mary Eddie Scott Jones, John Jordan, Charles Irwin Junkin, and William F. Junkin.
  - Jackson, George (Box 6, Folder 118)
    This folder contains personal correspondence between George Jackson and Mrs. Moore regarding real estate. Dated August 17th, 1907.
    Jackson, George
  - Jackson, Thomas "Stonewall" (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Jackson, Thomas "Stonewall" - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Jackson, Thomas "Stonewall" - Biography (Box 6, Folder 121)
    This folder contains a copy of "The Southern Churchman" from 1944 with a biographical piece on Jackson. Also holds an undated poem from an anoynmous author. Furthermore, there is a silver gellatin photo of a personal correspondence between Jackson and a fellow Confederate General.
  - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 122)
    This folder contains multiple photo negatives and a developed silver gellatin photograph of a Thomas Jefferson letter related to the Natural Bridge, dated July 1st, 1809. A facsimilie of the letter is also included.
    Jefferson, Thomas
  - Jerome, Chauncy (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Johnston, Abner Nash (Box 6, Folder 124)
    Johnston, Abner Nash
  - Johnston Family (Box 6, Folder 125)
    This folder includes a number of photos that portray personal correspondence to and from Johnston, dated between 1798 to 1805. Furthermore the folder has a prize awarded to Anna Johnston in chemistry from the Lexington Female Academy.
    Johnston family
  - Jones, Mary Eddie Scott (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Jordan, John (Box 6, Folder 127)
    This folder contains a copy of the magazine "The Iron Worker," dated August 1957, with a biographical piece on John Jordan.
    Jordan, John
  - Jordan, John - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Jordan, John - Biography (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Jordan, John - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Jordan, Captain John (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Junkin, Charles Irwin (Box 6, Folder 132)
    Junkin, Charles Irwin
  - Junkin, William F. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    Junkin, William F.
- K-L (Box 7, Folder 134-157)
  Aldine Kieffer, Ann E. Kirkpatrick, James F. Knick, Eva Jordan Krebs, Leech Family, John Legeune, Leguene address, John Letcher, John Letcher Jr., Andrew Lewis, John Lewis, Margaret Lewis, Dr. Alfred Leyburn, John Doak Lilley,
  - Kieffer, Aldine (Box 7, Folder 134)
    Kieffer, Aldine Silliman
  - Kieffer, Aldine - Musical Sheetbooks (Box 7, Folder 135)
    This folder contains two books of sheet music - "The New Harmonia Sacra: A Compilation of Church Music" by Joseph Funk's Sons published by Glen Publishing Company Printers in 1826, as well as "The Star of Bethlehem" edited by J.H. Hail and J.H. Ruebush published 1889.
  - Kirkpatrick, Ann E. (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Knick, James F. (Box 7, Folder 137)
    Knick, James F.
  - Krebs, Eva Jordan (Box 7, Folder 138)
    Krebs, Eva Jordan
  - Leech Family (Box 7, Folder 139)
    This folder includes tax forms for the Leech family dated 1889 and 1890, one of which deals with Thomas Leech's military status as a tax exemption.
    Lynch Family
  - Lejeune, Eugenia (Box 7, Folder 140)
    Lejeune, Eugenia Dickinson
  - Lejeune, John (Box 7, Folder 141)
    Lejeune, John
  - Lejeune, John - Address (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Letcher, John Seymour (Box 7, Folder 143)
    Letcher, John S. (John Seymour)
  - Letcher, John Seymour - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 144)
    This folder includes two business cards with John Letcher's signature. No dates available.
  - Letcher, John Jr. (Box 7, Folder 145)
    Letcher, John, Jr.
  - Lewis, Andrew (Box 7, Folder 146)
    Lewis, Andrew
  - Lewis, Andrew Continued (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Lewis, John (Box 7, Folder 148)
    This folder includes one photo negative and one developed silver gellatin photograph of John Lewis' home, Fort Lewis, as it stood in 1925 outside of Staunton, Virginia.
    Lewis, John
  - Lewis, Margaret Lynn (Box 7, Folder 149)
    Lewis, Margaret Lynn
  - Lewis, Margaret - The Commonplace Book (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Leyburn, Alfred (Box 7, Folder 151)
    Leyburn, Alfred
  - Lilley, John Doak (Box 7, Folder 152)
    Lilley, John Doak
  - Lyle, Duncan A. (Box 7, Folder 153)
    Lyle, Duncan Campbell
  - Lyle Family (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Lyle, John Blair - Notes on Virginia Cavalcade (Box 7, Folder 155)
    Contains undated photo negatives and developed photos of John Blair Lyle's tombstone.
  - Lyle, John Blair - Correspondence Concerning Virginia Cavalcade (Box 7, Folder 156)
    Lyle, John Blair
  - Lyle, John Blair - Papers (Box 7, Folder 157)
- Lee (Box 8, Folder 158-188)
  - Lee, Cader (Box 8, Folder 158)
    Cader, Lee
  - Lee, Fitzhugh (Box 8, Folder 159)
    This folder contains a letter between J.H. Letcher and Fitzhugh Lee with his signature. Dated May 25th, 1893.
    Lee, Fitzhugh
  - Lee, George Washington Custis (Box 8, Folder 160)
    Original typescript and manuscripts relating to reminiscences of G.W.C. Lee's time as President of Washington and Lee, and his time in Lexington.
    Lee, George Washington Custis
  - Lee, Henry (Box 8, Folder 161)
    Lee, Henry
  - Lee, Mildred Childe (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Lee, Robert Edward (Box 8, Folder 163)
    This folder contains four separate portraits of General Robert Edward Lee. All are undated.
    Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward)
  - Lee Memorial - Unveiling Program, Richmond, 1890-05-29 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    Program from the Unveiling of the Robert E. Lee Memorial in Richmond, Virginia. 2nd Edition. Dated 1890.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Copies of Letters (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Lee, Robert Edward (Box 8, Folder 166)
    This folder includes a pamphlet entitled "The True Story of General Order No. 9 - General Lee's Farewell Address to the Army of Northern Virginia," published by Lee Museum Committee at WLU. Published 1928.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Copies of Ceremonial Panphlets at the Presidential Inauguration of Robert E. Lee at Washington College, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    Four copies of "Ceremonies connected with the Inauguration of the Mausoleum and the Unveiling of the Recumbent Figure of General Robert Edward Lee." Dated 1883.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 168)
    This folder includes a copy og "Shenandoah Valley Magazine" from November 1980 that has a biographical piece on Lee's Lexington Home. Also includes Lee Memorial Fund magazine from 1921 and article, "Where the Past Isn't Even Past," by Peter J. Boyer, on the battles dividing Lexington, Virginia, THE WEEKLY STANDARD, November 26, 2018.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Commemorative Church Programs (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Eulogies in Washington College newspaper "Southern Collegian", 1870-10-15 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    This folder contains a copy of the newspaper "Southern Collegian" from October 15th, 1870 with the obituary of General Robert E. Lee.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Copies of "General Lee at Gettysburg, A Paper Read Before the Military Historical Society of Massachusetts, on the Fourth of April, 1905.", 1905-04-04 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    This folder includes a copy of James Power Smith's paper on General Lee at Gettysburg, which was delivered in April 1905. Published by R.E. Lee Camp, No. 1, Confederate Veterans from Richmond, VA.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "General Robert E. Lee", an Address by John Wesley Hill, Typescript., 1924-05 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "Lee Jackson Day" an address by Dr. Harry D. Campbell, 1925-01-19 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward); Campbell, Henry Donald
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "Robert E. Lee at the Battle of the Wilderness," Poem Manuscript, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Southern Collegian, Lee Number, Volume 39, Number 3, 1907-01-19 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    Soft-bound copy of Southern Collegian, Volume XXXIX, Number 3, "Lee Number", Robert E. Lee Centennial.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "Robert E. Lee, Soldier, Patriot, Educator" Pamphlet, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "Robert E. Lee: Churchman", by Marshall W. Fishwick, Historiographer, Diocese of Southwestern Virginia. (Box 8, Folder 177)
    "Robert E. Lee: Churchman", by Marshall W. Fishwick, Historiographer, Diocese of Southwestern Virginia.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - "War and Work," by Colonel William Couper (Box 8, Folder 178)
    This folder contains "War and Work" by Colonel William Couper - an address delivered before the Rockbridge County (VA.) Historical Society. Dated April 22nd, 1940.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Papers Concerning Lee (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Lee, Robert - Traveller (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Traveller's Silhouette Postcard (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Lee Family (Box 8, Folder 182)
    Lee family
  - Lee Family (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Lee Family - "The Lee Girls" Paper by Mary P. Coulling (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 185)
    This folder includes two sketched of furnishing inside the former home of Robert E. Lee. Undated.
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 186)
    Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward); Wickham, Henry Taylor
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Lee, Robert Edward - Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 188)
- M-Mc (Box 9, Folder 189-216)